to prove that the set of integers is
accountable set we have to find a
one-to-one and onto function from the
natural numbers to the integers to do
that we imagine the integers form a
doubly infinite line of dots and we
start at zero and spiral out like this
we see that every integer will be hit
once and only once to make this more
formal we can Define the function f of x
equal to X plus one over two if x is odd
and negative X over 2 if x is even and
this gives the required one to one and
onto map from the natural numbers to the
integers
we can do something similar to prove
that Z Cross C is a countable set we
plot the integer coordinate points in
the real plane as shown beginning at
zero zero Des McHale showed this spiral
which will eventually visit every single
integer coordinate point in the real
plane therefore this spiral proves the
existence of a one to one and onto map
from the natural numbers to pairs of
integers can you find a formula for the
one to one and onto map guaranteed by
this spiral